<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--
  Copyright 2010-2013 Hippo B.V. (http://www.onehippo.com)

  Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
  you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
  You may obtain a copy of the License at

    http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

  Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
  distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
  WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
  See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
  limitations under the License.
-->
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Release Notes</title>
    <subtitle>Release Notes</subtitle>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section name="Release Notes">
      <subsection name="2.07.09">
        <ul>
          <li>Pom and documentation improvements</li>
        </ul>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="2.07.08">
        <ul>
          <li>HIPPLUG-481: support in the &lt;properties:property /&gt; tag for formatting a property value with nested
              tag &lt;properties:param /&gt;.</li>
        </ul>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="2.07.07">
        <ul>
          <li>HIPPLUG-439: improved cache invalidation when using CachingPropertiesManagerImpl.</li>
        </ul>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="2.07.06">
        <ul>
          <li>Tried to solve HIPPLUG-439 but introduced a bug: please don't use this version.</li>
        </ul>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="2.07.05">
        <ul>
          <li>HIPPLUG-423: Fix NullPointerException in CachingPropertiesManagerImpl when locale is not given.</li>
        </ul>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="2.07.04">
        <ul>
          <li>HIPPLUG-293: Add support for a language parameter on the property tag.</li>
        </ul>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="2.07.03">
        <ul>
          <li>Compatibility with CMS 7.7 (2.22.xx) and HST 2.24.xx.</li>
          <li>French translations on properties documents folder queries.</li>
        </ul>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="2.07.02">
        <ul>
          <li>Adding request.getLocale() to the PropertiesManager#getPropertiesBean call within the jsp tag &lt;properties:property /&gt;.</li>
          <li>Using org.hippoecm.hst.tag.HstTagSupport as base for PropertyTag.</li>
          <li>Added CMS queries new-properties-document and new-properties-folder to be set as foldertype property on folders.</li>
        </ul>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="2.07.01">
        <ul>
          <li>
            Support for translated properties documents in site:<br/>
            - <span style="color: red">Note: API change!</span><br/>
            Added a java.util.Locale argument to the PropertiesManager#getPropertiesBean methods, resulting in three extra methods.<br/>
            - Introduced AbstractPropertiesManager implementation class for extendability.
          </li>
          <li>Support for a Spring configured default location that is outside of the site content root.<br/>
            <span style="color: red">Note: behaviour change!</span><br/>
            If the property 'defaultDocumentLocation' of PropertiesManager starts with slash ('/'), the
            location is retrieved relative to repository root, not relative to the bean given in API call.
            When upgrading, current implementations should remove any starting slash in order to be backwards compatible. </li>
          <li>Added a CMS configuration item (a filter on configuration browser) to hide the properties namespace from doc type editor.</li>
        </ul>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="2.07.00">
        <ul>
          <li>Compatibility with CMS 7.6 (2.20.00 and up) and HST 2.22.xx.</li>
        </ul>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="2.06.00">
        <ul>
          <li>Compatibility with CMS 7.5 (2.18.00 and up) and HST 2.20, including
              support in Properties document type for the multilanguage feature of CMS 7.5.
              PropertiesUpgrader18a reloads cnd and namespace.</li>
          <li>In CMS, made the properties list orderable.</li>
          <li>Formalized PropertiesManager API: retrieve PropertiesBeans instead of a Map, plus
              the introduction of static PropertiesUtil to get those maps.
              Previous methods are deprecated.</li>
          <li>Automatic fallback to default document in case of given document paths that are null.</li>
          <li>Removed the never used functionality of getting properties found at current bean's level and upwards.</li>
          <li>Introduction of the jsp tag &lt;properties:property /&gt; for easy retrieval of properties (labels) in the view layer.</li>
          <li>Improvements for cache invalidation in combination with properties documents in subfolders.</li>
        </ul>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="2.05.01">
        <ul>
          <li>Set hippo:version in the repository addon to the same as the end tag
            of the upgrader to CMS 7.4, which is 'v16a-properties'.
          </li>
        </ul>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="2.05.00">
        <ul>
          <li>
            Runs on Hippo CMS 7.4 (2.16.00 and up), involving a namespace bump to version 2.2.
          </li>
          <li>The Maven groupId of all artifacts has been changed to org.onehippo.forge.properties.</li>
        </ul>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="2.04.00">
        <ul>
          <li>
            Runs on Hippo CMS 7.3 (2.12.02 and up), involving a namespace bump to version 2.1.
          </li>
        </ul>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="2.03.00">
        <ul>
          <li>
            Introduction of a CachingPropertiesManager plus a PropertiesEventListener for
            invalidation of the cache, both to be set up in the site's Spring configuration.
          </li>
          <li>
            The artifacts 'properties-hst-api' and 'properties-hst-client' are merged,
            leaving only 'properties-hst-client'.
          </li>
          <li>
            Rename of the former PropertiesBean to PropertiesMap, plus introduction of
            a new PropertiesBean that can be used to cache properties documents.
          </li>
        </ul>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="2.02.00">
        <ul>
          <li>
            Runs on CMS 2.10.00 and up.
          </li>
        </ul>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="2.01.00">
        <ul>
          <li>
            Runs on CMS 2.09.00.
          </li>
        </ul>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="1.0x.xx">
        <ul>
          <li>
            Properties Component allowing to create simple CMS documents
            having a flat list of name/value pairs
          </li>
          <li>Easy locating and using the properties documents in a HST site frontend.</li>
        </ul>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
